Sony has had a bad year.
Sony's had a very bad year.
The year Sony has had has been bad
and it's getting worse.
An update from PlayStation Studios.
After careful consideration, we have
made the difficult decision to step away
from collaborating with Cojima
Productions on his project Fizzant. We
we continue to have great admiration for
Hideio Khjima's vision for the game. Our
relationship remains strong after three
decades of industry-leading
genredefinding creative cooperation, and
we look forward to continued close
collaboration with Hideio Khjima and his
award-winning independent studio in the
future.
PlayStation statement presents Fizzant
Split as a mutual stepaway after careful
consideration with future collaboration
expected. Cojima stated PlayStation
unexpectedly notified cancellation
midJune 2026, forcing a threemonth
search for a new partner.
Oh my god. Xbox swoops in to save
Kojima's stealth action game Fizzant
after PlayStation tried to cancel it.
Hideio Khjima's Fizzant moves from
PlayStation to Xbox as Death Stranding
creator plots TV and film projects with
new publishing partner.
Oh my god, we started with OD. Now our
partnership with Cojima Productions is
expanding with Vizant. We're just
getting started.
127,000 likes. Oh my god. It is actually
crazy that
everybody thought like whenever Asha
Sharma took over, people were like,
"Okay, it's this really young Indian
woman." Everybody thought this was going
to be like a DEI hire thing. People were
like super super skeptical about it. And
it's just been nothing but W's.
It's been nothing but [__] W's. And I
think people should remember that. As
confirmed earlier by our official
channels in midJune of this year, this
is from Hideio Khjima. Uh we
unexpectedly received notice from
PlayStation Studios that they would
cancel Fizzant project. Fizzant is an
important project to me personally and
to Cojima Productions. Determined to
keep the project alive, we have spent
the last 3 months searching tirelessly
for a new partner. In the source, in the
course of seeking advice and pursuing
negotiations with people between many
fields, we found an Xbox, a partner of
whom we share a common vision for the
future, and we have decided to team up
with them once again. Please rest
assured that the development of Fizzant,
our genredefining action espionage
title, is ongoing and will continue
moving forward.
Oh my god.
I really think Cojima leaving
PlayStation is like it's like Xbox
selling Halo.
I mean, Cojima, like he that was like
one of their main things
really. Like I I feel like Cojima is
like super Sony coded. Like it's super
PlayStation coded and it has been for 30
years.
To have this happen is insane.
It's accurate. Yeah. When I think of
Cojima, what console do you think of? I
think of PlayStation.
I do. I'm thinking of PlayStation. What
the [__] is this? Nobody knows that
Fizzant was going to sell. Death
Stranding 2 didn't sell well. I think
Sony can't afford any major losses.
Death Stranding 2 didn't sell well.
I don't think that's true. I thought it
did well. It did reasonably well, but
not as well as the first game. Yeah,
duh. I mean, okay, sure. It was a
continuation of the narrative of the
first game, as far as I know. At a
certain point, you have to ask yourself,
what are you doing this for?
You need to have games like Death
Stranding. Even if Death Stranding
doesn't make good money, it's an
artistic masterpiece.
I played the first Death Stranding. What
a beautiful game. Oh my god.
It's not even at a certain point you
have to and I know you're a company and
everything like this, but you you have
to I mean, come on, man. You can't make
this work.
You can't do this at all. What the [__]
is going on? Amazon Delivery Simulator.
You are trying to make the game into
something that it's not.
You need to let the game take you on an
adventure yourself. You need to stop
trying to make every single video game
an action combat adventure with bosses,
world progression, leveling up, and uh
levels.
You need to take a step back and
experience the game for what it is.
That's the way I look at it. The game is
boring as [__]
5 million people said no. It wasn't
okay. Her smile is frying. She knew she
hit the jackpot.
Oh my god.
Wow. If you had showed me this photo two
years ago, I would have told you that it
was AI. Like even if even if Ashes
Chararma was there, right? Like let's
say she was. I would have never believed
this. This is unbelievable. PlayStation
in 2026. End Destiny. End physical
gaming forever. End porting exclusives
to PC. Completely lose Hideio Khojima.
Attempt to cancel Cojima's next Metal
Gear franchise. Cojima cuts ties
entirely and goes to Xbox. Force your
single player studios to make live
service games. Concord happens. Proceed
to cancel most of them, losing years of
development time and billions of
dollars. Buy Bluepoint and have them
make a live service rather than remakes.
Close Bluepoint down before they release
any games. Start selling vertical stands
rather separately rather than having
them come with the console. Console
prices at an all-time high. Large scale
video game websites like IGN notoriously
rate AAA releases on a scale of 7 to 10.
A major platform exclusive like Horizon
Forbidden West or God of War Ragnarok
usually reviews around an 8.5 to a nine.
A six is catastrophic. Last time I
recall a game launching this big with
scores scores this low was Suicide Squad
killed the Justice League, which turns
out I think it killed that studio,
didn't it? Uh, which resulted in the
publisher taking a $200 million loss.
You do not spend $300 million to have a
AAA studio employing hundreds of people
to spend 5 years making a 6 out of 10
video game. Reviews like this will
dissuade people from even playing the
game that were going to buy it. This is
a disaster for Sony. I should have paid
the journalists more for this fake
review. Yeah, I guess so. I can't wait
to play this game. I can't wait. This is
going to be amazing. 300 million USD
budget. Let me see here. $35 million.
So, they they're spend they spent $35
million to get a six.
It's almost shocking that you can [__]
up that bad. It really is. Like that's
impressive that you can be that big of a
piece of [__] Um, Marvel's Wolverine,
slick and satisfying combat wears thin
well before its conclusion. So much so
that even its strong character work
can't save it from being anything more
than okay. And Wolverine got a six by
IGN. Wolverine reviews are finally here.
6 out of 10. 6 out of 10. 6 out of 10.
Skill up, not recommended. 8.5 out of
10. 8.5 out of 10, eight out of 10,
eight out of 10, eight out of 10, seven
out of 10, seven and seven, and so it's
not really looking that good, guys. They
made a Wolverine game for the average
Tik Tok user. What is this?
You probably think I was cherry-picking
in the intro, so here are some other
examples of how Insomniac have hidden
these chests.
Where? WHAT'S IN WHAT'S BEHIND THE
WHAT'S BEHIND THE BOX?
Holy [__]
Holy [__] Look where it is.
>> You said underground security.
>> Wait, wait, wait. I think I know where
it is. It's behind there.
>> Bulletproof.
>> It's like that TV.
>> There should be an elevator.
>> Yep, there it is. This is the sound
design. Listen to this.
>> Center of its badness is one thing that
I think is particularly important to
talk about. I would argue that the
defining characteristic of Marvel's
Wolverine is a design philosophy that
assumes the player is extremely stupid.
It starts here with some combat, and
we'll talk about this a lot more
throughout the review, but combat in
this game is not good. It is extremely
one-dimensional, spammy, sloppy, and
repetitive. But like I said, we will
talk more about it later. Combat ends,
and the first thing that happens is that
Wolverine talks to himself to remind the
player what their current objective is.
Oh, so he doesn't have like a secret
like a gauntlet or a robot or like a
fairy to tell him like, "Hey [__] Hey
[__] go over there."
>> Hell are you Red?
>> Logan does this constantly throughout
the game. So much so that it would make
Aloy herself blush. There is only one
way out of this area, but even then we
still get a scent line, which is
essentially like a GPS guy that we get
in an openw world game, only it's here
in this very narrow linear action game.
The overwhelming majority of levels in
this game will see you following this
GPS scent line for either a short or an
extended period of time. And for the
record, I know that Logan has enhanced
senses, including smell and hearing, but
the way this aspect of his character has
been
>> My favorite part about this entire
video, you guys aren't seeing it, is the
plus five experience just coming up
randomly as he's playing the game. Who
decided to put that into the game? Who
thought to themselves, you know what the
Wolverine game needs? Random experience
pop-ups notifying you that you're
gaining experience while playing the
game. Who asked for this? Really? Nobody
wanted this? This is insane.
>> Character has been realized in the video
game is so heavy-handed that robs the
player of their agency. It ruins the
potential for exploration and discovery
experience. This scentline GPS guide is
interrupted by an entirely new GPS
guide. A set of routes that magically
springs up from out of nowhere and lead
>> There's two GPS guides. Isn't that going
to confuse the player? us slightly to
the left because I guess we couldn't
have been trusted to spot this on our
own. Through this door is one of the
nightmare challenges which are gameplay
scenarios that are meant to be very
challenging and allow us to unlock
Logan's lost memories. This challenge is
a traversal based obstacle course. The
game has no real traversal systems to
speak of. So, it's essentially just
holding up on the stick for 50 seconds
while pressing jump occasionally. And
heaven forbid you might at any point be
unsure where to go because the entire
trail, which is strictly linear, mind
you, is signposted with white cloth,
white paint, and actual flashing red
lights. This is the first time I've done
this challenge, by the way, and I
immediately get the fastest possible
time. I step out of the nightmare, and
Logan again emotes with the same voice
line he said earlier to remind me what I
am doing. Where the hell are you, Red? I
can see in front of me the GPS sent line
I now need to follow. But just in case
I've missed it, an additional UI prompt.
There's another one. Oh, there it is.
Hey, [__] Hey, [__] You're not
getting confused, are you? You're Are
you going the wrong way? Uh-oh. Slaps
down.
>> I can't wait to watch a DSP super cut of
him playing this game and still doing it
wrong
and then doing the same thing myself.
It's going to be amazing. It It really
is. it like I'm going to mess something
up in this game. This game was made by
women. Of course, it was
>> on top of the scent line to remind me
that that's where follow in the
>> It's true, but most gamers aren't that
smart. I mean, but this is on another
level, right?
>> Insomniac's spin on Wolverine, played by
Liam McIntyre, is interesting because
most of the Wolverine that you see in
the movies or the TV shows paints
Wolverine as a bit of an [__] who
just so happens to have a heart of gold.
But here, Insomniac's Logan is a
genuinely nice guy. He's not a lone
wolf, but rather a Insomniac's been
>> He's not a lone wolf.
Wait, what do you mean he's not a lone
wolf?
That's like his entire story.
He's a nice guy. I mean, I would argue
that Wolverine is your typical
anti-hero. He is like um Deadpool. Um
kind of like Batman. Uh he's like uh I
would say Illan in World of Warcraft.
Like I I don't know. Yeah. I mean it's I
I Yeah, like the Punisher kind of blade.
I don't know about that, right? Uh yeah,
Venom. I think Venom could be a good
example. They're changing everything. I
don't know. He's like a chaotic good.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's just full clip.
Okay, let's see the full clip. played by
Liam McIntyre is interesting because
most of the Wolverine that you see in
the movies or the TV shows paints
Wolverine as a bit of an [__] who
just so happens to have a heart of gold.
But here, Insomniac Logan is a genuinely
nice guy. He's not a lone wolf, but
rather a team player. He's not
short-tempered, but rather quite patient
with those around him. He's good with
kids. He says sorry when he does the
wrong thing. The list goes on. A bad
faith reading of this would be like they
made Wolverine soft, but that's not it
at all. He's still as ferocious and anim
animalistic as you'd expect him to be
when it's time to throw down, but he's
more affable when he's around those he
trusts. And maybe this won't be your
favorite rendition ever, but it's an
interesting one that gives Logan a lot
of natural emotional depth early on
without having to excavate that from
under the more traditional angry outer
layer we're so used to seeing. Oh,
>> I think that we need to get back to the
characters like Master Chief, Solid
Snake, Ryden,
um Raiden, and and again, Leon Kennedy.
Yeah, Leon Kennedy, it's like you like
Leon Kennedy is the best example of how
to do this the right way is he's
obviously a badass. He's obviously a
hard ass, but when it comes time to
protect a little girl or to save a
woman, he's there and he's doing it
right. That is, in my opinion, that is
like pinnacle behavior, right? That's
what you need to do. Dante from Devil
May Cry. Yes, exactly. All of this soft,
weird [__] This was designed by a
woman.
>> Hey, and um
>> it was
>> and uh found
>> everybody knows it.
>> Would you mind when it back?
>> And by the way, there's nothing wrong
with me saying this. Like, I've had to
sit through the last 15 years hearing
about how, oh, you can tell this this
girl's armor was designed by a man.
Well, how can you tell? Well, because
she looks attractive in it, and I don't
like that. It's like, no. No. And And
now at this point, bro, like, I have to
I I have to see this [__]
>> I have to say it.
>> Um,
>> Geralt. Yeah.
>> Happy birthday.
>> Okay.
>> Jesus.
>> Played by Lee.
>> Jesus Christ, man. Every superhero must
act at least halfway close to
Spider-Man. Yeah. It's just they're
afraid of having any characters that are
like this. Quick time events that
complete themselves
>> throughout this review. But the honest
truth is that the more I played this
game, the more angry it made me. Like
for example, it was only toward the back
end of the game that I realized that you
actually don't have to press any buttons
during quicktime events. The game will
automatically complete them for you,
even if you don't press anything. Like
this clip right here.
>> Wow.
So, he's not even doing anything.
He just fails every quick time event
>> and it doesn't even make a difference.
>> What are we doing here? Like, you've got
a game where people die in
>> By the way, guys,
it's crazy, isn't it? It's really crazy
how the dumbest and most completely
surface level accusation turns out to
just have so much validity.
It really does.
>> Like you've got a game die in horrific
circumstances again and again. It's M17
plus rated in the US. Insomniac have
said repeatedly that they want a gritty,
mature story that isn't pulling any
punches. A story intended for
>> It's also, you know what I also don't
like? Yellow is Perry and red is Dodge.
Can you come up with something better
than that? Like I feel like we've had
this now for like eight years.
Let's move past this. Adults and yet we
get a game that literally plays itself
at times. And when you're forced to put
hands on the controller, Insomniac are
so terrified that you might experience a
fleeting moment of uncertainty about
where to go and what to do that they
build multiple overlapping gameplay
systems to keep you constantly wrapped
in cotton wool. Three separate clues
pointing you to hidden chess. One of
them borderline comical in its
presentation. Playing Marvel's Wolverine
is like bowling with the kids bumpers
on, but the bumpers are so narrow that
it's impossible to score anything other
than a strike. Oh, and the ball throws
itself, too. Am I exaggerating? No, I am
not. If you play this for yourself, you
will see what I mean. This is
ridiculous. It's like the Mario focus
mme brought to life, and it's a genuine
tipping point. Like I guarantee you that
Marvel's Wolverine will serve as a
talking point in game design meetings
where developers will be like, "Uh, do
we really need that yellow paint there?
We don't want to go full Marvel's
Wolverine, do we?" That will be the
legacy of this game. A true wakeup call
and an expiration date for this
philosophy of AAA game design that feels
the need to coddle the lowest common
denominator at the expense of the rest
of us. I don't recommend this.
>> Wow.
He is now. Wow. That is [__] brutal.
Oh my god. And this is wait
this dude
the developers are already writing
applications to McDonald's just in case.
This game is not going to meet
commercial expectations unlike the
Spider-Man game. Yeah. The difference is
that the Spider-Man game was good. Like
I watched people I didn't play the game
honestly. I but I watched Kai play it
whenever because he played the whole
thing and it looked really good. This is
one of Sony's exclusives. Yeah, this is
one of Sony's exclusives. So, let's
think about um a a nondescript uh list
of Sony um great Sony exclusives.
Concord
Wolverine.
Um
it's not looking good, guys.
Spider-Man. Yep. Spider-Man.
I mean, it's just Yeah. Intergalactic.
Yeah. I mean, someh isn't. No, they got
rid of that. Now Cojima is working with
Xbox. So, this is just really, guys, I
have to tell you that Western video game
design.
It's over.
I want you to understand this.
There are no more western or sorry
American video game design.
It's over guys. Like we had we had a
good run and for a little bit of time we
really thought that things could have
been good but at this point it's over.
I'm sorry guys except for Rockstar. If
Grand Theft Auto 6 fails I think that
Trump should just make it illegal to
make a video game if you have a studio
of over a 100 people. Like if you're an
American studio and you have more than a
hundred people working on a video game,
the Delta Force comes in at the middle
of the workday, right? Let's say it's
3:30 in the afternoon and they arrest
and put every single person in that uh
in that in the building in like
Guantanamo Bay or something like that
for suspected terrorism on the uh on the
on the mail hobby.
>> Yeah, this is it. Western game design is
it's just over.
American game design. Sorry, American
American American game design. It's
over. Sorry, guys.